<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-26T21:50:36-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rmc’s site</title><entry><title type="html">101 Mini Golf World - Another bland DSiWare</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/101-minigolf-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="101 Mini Golf World - Another bland DSiWare" /><published>2022-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/101-minigolf-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/101-minigolf-world.html"><![CDATA[<p>101 MiniGolf World by Teyon is a golf game for the DSi. It's nothing special as far as DSiWare goes.
<br><br>
The game starts up with a nice tutorial on how to play. It goes over all the controls in about 20 seconds and doesn't leave you confused.
<br>
The controls are very straightforward, and I have no complaints in that regard. Use the touch screen to move the camera, and hit the ball icon when you're ready to shoot. To shoot, you slide the stylus against the touchscreen. Sliding faster makes the ball go further, and vice versa.
<br><br>
The gameplay itself is what you'd expect from a cheap DSi golf game. There are many obstacles that can make things a bit interesting, however they usually don't add any challenge as you can go around them in a single swing. And don't worry about wasting your swings. The game sets a really high par limit, which you will almost never fail to end within. The unchallenging gameplay makes the game get stale pretty quickly.
<br><br>
The visuals are average, with some very basic 3D models. If the models obstruct your view while playing, they'll fade out. However, some small objects such as grass or flowers will not fade away, and can sometimes make it hard to see your ball.
<br><br>
In the end, this game was one of the more forgettable ones. It was kinda fun for a little bit, but didn't have anything challenging or interesting to offer. I'd give this a 6/10.</p>]]></content><author><name>Teyon</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[101 MiniGolf World by Teyon is a golf game for the DSi. It's nothing special as far as DSiWare goes. The game starts up with a nice tutorial on how to play. It goes over all the controls in about 20 seconds and doesn't leave you confused. The controls are very straightforward, and I have no complaints in that regard. Use the touch screen to move the camera, and hit the ball icon when you're ready to shoot. To shoot, you slide the stylus against the touchscreen. Sliding faster makes the ball go further, and vice versa. The gameplay itself is what you'd expect from a cheap DSi golf game. There are many obstacles that can make things a bit interesting, however they usually don't add any challenge as you can go around them in a single swing. And don't worry about wasting your swings. The game sets a really high par limit, which you will almost never fail to end within. The unchallenging gameplay makes the game get stale pretty quickly. The visuals are average, with some very basic 3D models. If the models obstruct your view while playing, they'll fade out. However, some small objects such as grass or flowers will not fade away, and can sometimes make it hard to see your ball. In the end, this game was one of the more forgettable ones. It was kinda fun for a little bit, but didn't have anything challenging or interesting to offer. I'd give this a 6/10.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">101 Pinball World - The worst pinball game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/101-pinball-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="101 Pinball World - The worst pinball game" /><published>2022-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/101-pinball-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/101-pinball-world.html"><![CDATA[101 Pinball World, released by Tenyon, is the worst pinball game imaginable for DSi. It looks, feels, and sounds like a cheap and rushed piece of crap... probably because it is.
<br><br>
This game has 4 "different" worlds (each themed after halloween, space, wizards, and pirates), with each 34 levels each. Each level was sloppily put together with repetitive graphics and game breaking object placement. All levels in one world are the exact same as all levels in the other worlds, just with a the textures changed. Most of those levels play okay, but some are god awful. There are many times that the bumpers are placed so that if a side spring saves your ball, the bumper will send it right back down. Or so that when you first launch your ball, the bumpers will send it back to the start. Or so that when a ball comes out of a chute, the bumpers will send it right down the middle and through your paddles. You get the idea.
<br><br>
If you somehow manage to ignore the horrible level design and look, you'll notice a lot of other things wrong with this game. The ball jerkily jumps around the screen. Sometimes it just stops for half a second and then appears halfway across the screen. When it continues moving, it can suddenly appear right by your paddles, giving you no time to react.<br>
The ball will also get stuck over and over. It will wedge itself into corners and you can't free it. You can shake the table as many times as you want, but it'll just sit there doing absolutely nothing.
<br><br>
Lastly, the music. Well no, it's not really music. It's just noise. Everything (with the exception of the title screen) is completely out of tune. I really don't know what to say other than it's bad. Just listen for yourself <a href="https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=xAFhHeACwXg" target="_blank">here</a>.
<br><br>
Overall, this game is awful. Poor graphics, sound, level design, gameplay, and it's full of bugs. There's nothing that makes this game good or enjoyable. 1/10. Don't play it.]]></content><author><name>Teyon</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[101 Pinball World, released by Tenyon, is the worst pinball game imaginable for DSi. It looks, feels, and sounds like a cheap and rushed piece of crap... probably because it is. This game has 4 "different" worlds (each themed after halloween, space, wizards, and pirates), with each 34 levels each. Each level was sloppily put together with repetitive graphics and game breaking object placement. All levels in one world are the exact same as all levels in the other worlds, just with a the textures changed. Most of those levels play okay, but some are god awful. There are many times that the bumpers are placed so that if a side spring saves your ball, the bumper will send it right back down. Or so that when you first launch your ball, the bumpers will send it back to the start. Or so that when a ball comes out of a chute, the bumpers will send it right down the middle and through your paddles. You get the idea. If you somehow manage to ignore the horrible level design and look, you'll notice a lot of other things wrong with this game. The ball jerkily jumps around the screen. Sometimes it just stops for half a second and then appears halfway across the screen. When it continues moving, it can suddenly appear right by your paddles, giving you no time to react. The ball will also get stuck over and over. It will wedge itself into corners and you can't free it. You can shake the table as many times as you want, but it'll just sit there doing absolutely nothing. Lastly, the music. Well no, it's not really music. It's just noise. Everything (with the exception of the title screen) is completely out of tune. I really don't know what to say other than it's bad. Just listen for yourself here. Overall, this game is awful. Poor graphics, sound, level design, gameplay, and it's full of bugs. There's nothing that makes this game good or enjoyable. 1/10. Don't play it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AiRace Tunnel - Great time waster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/airacetunnel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AiRace Tunnel - Great time waster" /><published>2022-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/airacetunnel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/airacetunnel.html"><![CDATA[If you haven't played AiRace Tunnel from QubicGames, you're missing out.
<br><br>
AiRace Tunnel is a fairly straightforward game. The goal is to fly a plane through a series of tunnels, while avoiding obstacles within them. There are 6 tunnels of varying degrees of difficulty, 2 of which are infinite.
<br><br>
Normally a game like this might get boring after a while, but this one manages to stay fun. As you play, your plane moves faster and faster, and the obstacles become harder to avoid. At first it is fairly easy, but it will suddenly take a lot of concentration, and even the slightest wrong movement could make you crash.
<br><br>
Controls in this game are <i>really</i> well done. You've got touchscreen or button controls, both of which feel very responsive, and you can switch between left or right handed mode.<br>As a lefty, I love not having to hold the stylus in my jittery right hand and having to waste my good hand on hitting a few buttons. So many games have this issue, and as a result are hard for me to play. Thanks for fixing that, AiRace Tunnel!
<br><br>
The graphics in this game are fairly good. The tunnels are highly detailed 3d models and look awesome. The UI, however, leaves much to be desired. It gives off a very flat and cheap feel. Because of this, at a first glance this game looked like another piece of crap DSi shovelware to me.
<br><br>
Overall, this game is really good. Great gameplay, it looks fine, and controls amazing. But due to the UI looking like crap, I'll have to take a point off and give this one a 9/10.]]></content><author><name>QubicGames</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you haven't played AiRace Tunnel from QubicGames, you're missing out. AiRace Tunnel is a fairly straightforward game. The goal is to fly a plane through a series of tunnels, while avoiding obstacles within them. There are 6 tunnels of varying degrees of difficulty, 2 of which are infinite. Normally a game like this might get boring after a while, but this one manages to stay fun. As you play, your plane moves faster and faster, and the obstacles become harder to avoid. At first it is fairly easy, but it will suddenly take a lot of concentration, and even the slightest wrong movement could make you crash. Controls in this game are really well done. You've got touchscreen or button controls, both of which feel very responsive, and you can switch between left or right handed mode.As a lefty, I love not having to hold the stylus in my jittery right hand and having to waste my good hand on hitting a few buttons. So many games have this issue, and as a result are hard for me to play. Thanks for fixing that, AiRace Tunnel! The graphics in this game are fairly good. The tunnels are highly detailed 3d models and look awesome. The UI, however, leaves much to be desired. It gives off a very flat and cheap feel. Because of this, at a first glance this game looked like another piece of crap DSi shovelware to me. Overall, this game is really good. Great gameplay, it looks fine, and controls amazing. But due to the UI looking like crap, I'll have to take a point off and give this one a 9/10.]]></summary></entry></feed>